Sami Mabrouk

 $Software\ Engineer\ |\ San\ Diego,\ CA\ (Remote)\ |\ 858.733.1242\ |\ \underline{samimabrouk10@gmail.com}\ |\ \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/mabrouk10/}\ |\ https://mabrouk10.github.io/portfolio/\ |\ github.com/mabrouk10/$

Summary

Software Engineer with strong analytical and logical skills dedicated to building and optimizing creative web applications that provide intuitive user experiences. Strong skills developed in critical thinking, leadership, communication and teamwork from previous work experiences as a Research Associate, Full Stack Developer Intern, Software QA Analyst and Software Engineer Intern.

Technical Skills

Languages:

- JavaScript
- Rubv
- HTML
- CSS
- Java

Frameworks:

- React
- Ruby on Rails

Version Control:

Git

Testing:

- lest
- Rspec

Databases:

- PostgreSQL
- Active Record

Other related skills:

- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Discrete Mathematics
- Statistics
- JIRA/Confluence

Experience

Family Proud | Software Engineer Intern | San Diego CA | January 2021 - Present

• Software Engineering Intern for a growing healthcare tech startup ensuring smooth processing of care and resources amongst patients and families in need

LEARN Academy | Software Engineer in Training | San Diego CA | November 2020 - January 2021

- 12 week full time coding bootcamp specializing in JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, and PostgreSQL
- Contributed to applications through extensive pair and mob programming
- Completed 480+ hours of direct coding experience
- Obtained proficiency in test-driven development

snaploT | Software QA Analyst | San Diego CA | August 2020 - November 2020

- Planned and coordinated testing activities using JIRA and Confluence
- Designed traceability matrices, test plans and test scripts for software requirements
- Managed and distributed assets and documentation from creative department to engineering team
- Conducted integration, version, regression, user acceptance testing

Orlando Inc | Full Stack Developer Intern | San Diego CA | September 2020 - October 2020

- Learning MEAN development stack (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js) stack to build applications for aviation schools
- Collaborating with UI/UX designers, full stack developers/engineers and CEO to create design decisions, reiterate group objectives and set future goals.

Explora | Research Associate | San Diego CA | April 2020 - May 2020

- Formulated and administered test articles through multiple routes in mice (PO, IP, IV, SQ)
- Routinely performed daily responsibilities in BSL I and BSL II conditions

Education

University of California, San Diego

June 2019

Bachelor of Science: General Biology (Completed)

Minor: Computer Science (In progress unable to register into Upper Division classes for the time being due to very limited seats in Computer Science department)